A Guide to the Sharon Bulova News Articles Collection, 1988-2019
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Sharon Bulova News Articles Collection, 1988-2019
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 06-106
3.5 linear feet
The Sharon Bulova News Articles Collection consists of 3.5 linear feet, spans the years 1988-2019, and includes news articles in the format of newspaper clippings, photocopies, computer printouts, and campaign pamphlets. Bulova’s staff maintained these files and referred to the collection as the “Bulova Record”.
Bulova, Sharon (1947-)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Transferred to the Virginia Room from Chairman Sharon Bulova’s office in November 2019 prior to her retirement from the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors.
Historical and Biographical Information
Sharon (Schuster) Bulova was born on December 6, 1947 to Mary and Lawrence K. Schuster Sr. in Pikesville, Maryland. At age 18, she married Richard T. Bulova and moved to Northern Virginia in 1966. In 1971, the couple moved to Kings Park West where she served two terms as president of the Kings Park West Civic Association. As president she became acquainted with Annandale District Supervisor Audrey Moore who hired her as a legislative staff aide in 1984.
In 1987, when Supervisor Moore left to successfully win a seat as Chairman of the Board of Supervisors, Bulova decided to run for Moore’s vacated seat. Bulova defeated Republican Patrick Mullins and went on to win re-election in the newly renamed Braddock District in 1991, 1995, 1999, 2003, and 2007. Bulova ran for Chairman of the Board of Supervisors in a special election on February 3, 2009 and won. Fairfax County residents re-elected her again in 2011 and 2015. On December 6, 2018, Bulova decided to not run for re-election and continued to lead the board until her term expired in December 2019.
During her eleven years as Chairman, Bulova guided the county through the Great Recession, ushered in new land use plans, welcomed Metro’s Silver Line to Tysons and Reston, updated the county’s environmental vision and created the Joint Environmental Task Force (JET), reduced homelessness by nearly fifty percent, re-engineered police policies and practices, and established a social and racial equity policy called One Fairfax.
Scope and Content
The Sharon Bulova News Articles Collection consists of 3.5 linear feet, spans the years 1988-2019, and includes news articles in the format of newspaper clippings, photocopies, computer printouts, and campaign pamphlets. Bulova’s staff maintained these files and referred to the collection as the “Bulova Record”. The clippings chronicle Bulova’s career and accomplishments dating back to 1988 when Bulova was Annandale and later Braddock District Supervisor and up through her tenure as Chairman of the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors in 2019.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Bulova, Sharon (1947-); Fairfax County Board of Supervisors
Container List
- Bulova Record 1988 news articles, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bulova Record 1989 news articles, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bulova Record 1990 news articles, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bulova Record 1991 news articles, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bulova Record 1992 news articles, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bulova Record 1993 news articles, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bulova Record 1994 news articles, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bulova Record 1995 news articles, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bulova Record 1996 news articles, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bulova Record 1997 news articles, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Bulova Record 1998 news articles (1 of 2), 1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Bulova Record 1998 news articles (2 of 2), 1998 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bulova Record 1999 news articles, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Bulova Record 2000 news articles, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Bulova Record 2001 news articles, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Bulova Record 2002 news articles, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Bulova Record 2003 news articles, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Bulova Record 2004 news articles, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Bulova Record 2005 news articles (1 of 2), 2005 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Bulova Record 2005 news articles (2 of 2), 2005 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Bulova Record 2006 news articles, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Bulova Record 2007 news articles (1 of 2), 2007 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Bulova Record 2007 news articles (2 of 2), 2007 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Bulova Record 2008 news articles (1 of 3), 2008 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Bulova Record 2008 news articles (2 of 3), 2008 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Bulova Record 2008 news articles (3 of 3), 2008 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Bulova Record 2009 news articles (1 of 3), 2009 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Bulova Record 2009 news articles (2 of 3), 2009 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Bulova Record 2009 news articles (3 of 3), 2009 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Bulova Record 2010 news articles, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Bulova Record 2011 news articles, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Bulova Record 2012 news articles (1 of 2), 2012 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Bulova Record 2012 news articles (2 of 2), 2012 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Bulova Record 2013 news articles (1 of 2), 2013 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Bulova Record 2013 news articles (2 of 2), 2013 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Bulova Record 2014 news articles, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Bulova Record 2015 news articles, 2015 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Bulova Record 2016 news articles, 2016 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Bulova Record 2017 news articles, 2017 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Bulova Record 2018-19 news articles, 2018-2019 (Box 7, Folder 5)